NAME AND CONTACT INFORMATION

Full name: ADEGUNTE Joshua Kayode

Current Residence: 1, GRA Ijokodo Area, Ibadan, Oyo State, Nigeria

Email: joshade37@gmail.com

Tel: +2348069559979

CAREER SUMMARY

Attentive Chef with seven years of experience handling catering and culinary activities Demonstrated history of success as a catering chef and instructor. Committed to delivering exceptional customer service, supervising operations, and delivering culinary excellence Dedicated to food safety and quality food service

SKILLS

- Staffing/ Training/ Instructing
- Dining Room/ Kitchen Operations
- Catering/ Banquets/ Events
- Customer Service/ Guest Relations

- Conferences/ Special Occasions
- Event Planning
- Budgeting/ Cost Reduction
- Food Safety/ Sanitation

WORK EXPERIENCE

Born Hotel, Ibadan, Nigeria 2022

Line Chef

- Preparing food according to recipes and instruction provided by the head chef or sous-chef
- Ensuring that all ingredients are prepared and organized before service
- Monitoring food inventory and ensuring that ingredients are stocked and rotated appropriately.

Glorious Star Catering Services, Ibadan, Nigeria 2019 – 2022

Catering Chef

- Delivered exceptional food and meals based on the anticipated number of guests, recipes, costs, portioning, menus, diet plans, temperature control procedures, and facility policies.
- Monitored work areas, serving lines, and eating areas to ensure safe food preparation and service environment while enforcing appropriate sanitation practices and safety precautions.

Nurse Nassir Apartment 2018 - 2022

Part-Time Private Chef

- I work with health care staff to ensure appropriate nutrition for each resident.
- Duties include practicing safe food handling.
- Planning of meals.
- I assist with purchasing food, recommending proper quantities and items based on resident demand and dietary needs.

Grace House Apartment, Ibadan, Nigeria 2019 - 2022

Part-Time Private Chef

- Planned and Coordinate Menu
- Foods Costing
- Nutrition Control

Event Planner

- Led the team in developing custom menus that allow us to go above and beyond client expectations.
- Planned, coordinated, and executed events Oversaw the planning and execution of logistics and operations for private parties, conferences, and special events.
- Managed vendor selection, hotel negotiation, on-site management, and program implementation.

Nissi Catering and Training Center, Ibadan, Nigeria 2012 – 2016

Chef Instructor

- Prepared culinary students to be profitable, effective foodservice leaders and entrepreneurs.
- Taught topics on quantity foods production, purchasing/inventory management, menu planning, cost control, and sustainability in a relatable form which improved students' knowledge.
- Demonstrated step-by-step cooking techniques to both novice and advanced cooks, connecting students to complex information through hands-on engagement.

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION

World Chef Academy	2023
 Certificate in Culinary Arts 	
Food Standards Agency, UK	2022
 Food Allergy and Intolerance 	
Royal Spices Academy, Oluyole, Ibadan	2022
 Certificate in Culinary Arts 	
Allison	2021
 Diploma in Hospitality and Tourist Management 	
Allison	2021
 Health and Safety in Food Service 	
Central Bank of Nigeria (CBN)	2017
 Entrepreneurship Certificate 	
M&B Beautify, Eleyele, Ibadan	2012
 Certification in Catering and Event Management 	
EDUCATION	

National Business and Technical Examinations Board

2020

Senior Secondary Certificate Examination (SSCE)

REFERENCES

To be provided on request